Alberto Roque Carrizo Fernández

contact@roquec.com | roquec.com | github.com/roquec | linkedin.com/in/roquec

Introduction

I am an experienced software engineer with a pragmatic approach, valuing simplicity in solutions. Highly independent and adept at self-learning, I seek opportunities to deliver genuine value to clients and society.

Skills

.NET C# Azure SQL Elasticsearch Git JavaScript Docker Microservices GQL SASS Powershell

Experience

2018-2022 | Senior Backend Engineer at NEOCLES (B2B e-commerce platform for fashion)

- Developed high-performance e-commerce APIs for thousands of concurrent users.
- Managed releases and maintenance for 5 segregated client production environments.
- Developed backend services receiving 10M+ import messages daily from external systems.
- · Led upgrade and configuration of 30+ Elasticsearch servers, saving thousands of euros monthly.
- · Worked directly with clients conducting fit-gap analyses to integrate new services.
- Technology stack .NET C# SQL Elasticsearch Azure Angular

2017-2018 | Fullstack Developer at INVESTEL (fleet management system)

- Led development of an AngularJS management application for internal use.
- Worked with designer on implementation of new Angular frontend for existing application.
- Evolved into a fullstack developer role, implementing new features and addressing backend bugs.
- · Implemented and documented OAuth service for external client authentication.
- Technology stack AngularJS C# SQL .NET Framework

Projects

2022-Present | Ship Navigation Application Winui3 C# .NET

- Designed and build Windows desktop application based on clients requirements.
- Integrated with Automatic Identification Systems (AIS) via serial port connection.

2023 | Portfolio Website: roquec.com Jekyll JavaScript SASS

- Developed custom SASS styling to imitate Visual Studio Code look.
- Created JavaScript solution for smooth SPA-like state through page navigations.
- Automated deployments, Lighthouse testing and reporting using GitHub Actions and Powershell.

Education

2019 | Microsoft Exam AZ-400 Designing and Implementing Microsoft DevOps Solutions.

2011-2016 | Bachelor's degree, Computer Software Engineering from University of Oviedo.

Languages

English | Full professional proficiency.



Spanish | Native.